### Contact

k.nugmanov@mail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kirilnugmanov (LinkedIn) zenitech.co.uk (Company)

github.com/cynicLT (Personal)

Top Skills

Hibernate

Spring

**Tomcat** 

### Languages

Lithuanian (Native or Bilingual)

English (Native or Bilingual)

Russian (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Learning Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)

How to Think Strategically

Java Memory Management: Values and References

**COBOL Essential Training** 

JMeter: Performance and Load Testing

### **Publications**

Cloud Application with Spring Cloud Stream and Apache Kafka

Locale independent error handling

Prevent start Spring application without profile defined

# Kiril Nugmanov

Solution Architect / Chapter Lead / Java Engineer

Kaunas, Kauno, Lithuania

## Summary

Development and maintenance of high scale applications using technologies like Spring Framework, JPA, JMS, JTA etc. Participation in full software development life cycle from idea to technical implementation.

Specialization: event sourcing, auto-scalable applications, cloud native application, performance oriented application implementation.

## Experience

Zenitech

5 years 9 months

Chapter Lead / Solution Architect April 2023 - Present (5 months)

Kaunas, Kauno, Lithuania

Enabling Java technology forum to expand professional experience in various topics. Defining technological expertise and demand from stakeholders technology forum wise. Supporting and motivating developer to build supportive environment to share knowledge and/or expertise in various subjects.

Solution Architect / Java Engineer

March 2020 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Supporting business initiatives and transition into implementation stage. Active assistance in software development and information gathering for successful implementation of business critical solutions.

Java Technical Lead

March 2018 - Present (5 years 6 months)

Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

From March 2018 I was promoted to Java Technical Lead.

Our vision for Zenitech was to create a very "human" workplace based on mutual respect, open and direct relationships with each other and with our customers. We are visionary and fanatic on technology and solutions and we take pride in what we do. Here you will feel welcomed by great colleagues, who are building a great team of friends.

Senior Java Developer
December 2017 - February 2018 (3 months)
Vilnius, Vilniaus, Lithuania

Starting from 1st of December I'm proud to be part of Zenitech team.

Zenitech are Agile experts and our teams will fully integrate within your existing workforce or provide whole delivery organisations consisting of Software Engineers, Business Analysts, Project Managers, SCRUM masters and Testers. Combined with our nearshore leverage through our offices in Lithuania and Romania we are able to rapidly scale these capabilities.

UAB Etnomedijos Intercentras 16 years 3 months Senior Java Developer

September 2008 - Present (15 years)

Vilnius, Lithuania

Untill 2013 was working for JSC "Etnomedijos Intercentras" as a senior Java developer with a strong SOA background. JSC "Etnomedijos Intercentras" provides robust applications for the G2G and/or G2B integration. There are several National development and support projects.

In the development project company providing full application development cycle. Projects are National scope thus there is strong demand for high availability distributed solutions. The main technology stack is following: Java EE, Spring, ORM (Hibernate), RDBMS (Oracle 10/11) and Apache Tomcat 6/7. We develop software using Agile Extreme programming. In several projects there was a demand for the integration layer thus as a robust solution I choose Oracle AS with BPEL processing engine. Architectural model of all projects is n-tier. I'm applying knowledge to develop stable software products in mission critical solutions. To simplify programmers' life constantly searching for better solutions in project management, continuous integration, testing.

In the support projects I'm responsible for the technical and architectural solutions. Additionally I'm mentoring other programmers and providing "best

practices" in a variety of application layers. We are using Apache Tomcat, Oracle SOA Suite and Oracle AS as an integration layer, data storage implemented using Oracle RDBMS in existing support projects.

Java Developer

June 2007 - September 2008 (1 year 4 months)

During my work as a Java programmer for JSC "Etnomedijos Intercentras" was a part of the team that was developing EDAS project. Oracle Middle ware products (Oracle Portal, Oracle Infrastructure) were used in this project. Oracle RDBMS was chosen as a solution for the data storage. Integration layer was implemented using Oracle BPM engine.

There were many challenges starting from performance optimization and re-factoring of development process. Due to the high demand - software development cycle was minimized and optimized to meet the requirements.

Being mentored by the best IT specialists my development skills start to increase rapidly. Within 1 year I became responsible for the development cycle in this project.

Alna Software Senior Java Developer February 2014 - December 2018 (4 years 11 months) A. Gostauto g. 40B, Vilnius, Lithuania

From February of 2014 start working in Alna Software as Senior Java developer. Alna Software is one of the major IT companies in the Baltic countries providing customised software solutions to customers all over the world. The company was established in 2004 following the merger of two software development divisions of the Alna Group developing broad-scale information systems for users in Lithuania and providing software outsourcing services to foreign customers.

Development of national scope high-load projects is done using distributed computing technologies like Hazelcast and ActiveMQ. Due to the exceptional availability requirements applications are developed using micro-service architectural approach. Variety of integrations and/or inter-communications being implemented using SOAP/REST protocols (REST in favour).

Barclays

Application Middleware Engineering – Java Application Platform Engineer

December 2013 - January 2014 (2 months)

Vilnius, Lithuania

For 3 months was working as Java application middleware engineer for Barclays Technology

Centre Ltd. Barclays Technology Centre Ltd is a division of Barclays - British multinational banking and financial services company headquartered in London. It is a universal bank with operations in retail, wholesale and investment banking, as well as wealth management, mortgage lending and credit cards. I'm assigned for the internal middleware development project.

In this internal project we develop cluster ware management utility for other internal teams. The main technology stack is following: JEE, Spring, Hibernate, ExtJS, In Memory Data Grid (Oracle Coherence), MS SQL DB. Apache Tomcat 6.

JSC "Naujos Sistemos An Intern June 2006 - October 2006 (5 months) Vytenio st. 50, LT-03229 Vilnius

While working for the JSC "Naujos Sistemos" was responsible for the implementation of provided web page design using proprietary CMS system. Every provided design solution was optimized for the variety of browsers and resolutions. General technological stack was PHP, XHTML, CSS, JavaScript and MySQL for the data storage.

On behalf of my work was part of the team responsible for development of "Vilnius City electronic mark book" (http://edienynas.vilnius.lt/). Implemented solution was PHP and Oracle based. Robust application system was developed using Agile approach for the software writing.

Also I was responsible for the administration of several Linux based servers. Was administrating MySQL RDBMS, POSIX based mail server.

## Education

Vilnius Gediminas Technical University Master's Degree, Data Mining (2007 - 2009)

Vilnius Gediminas Technical University
Bachelor's Degree, Engineering Informatics (2003 - 2007)